Emmanuel Podestá Junior

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

"All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given to us."

Summary _

I have 7+ years experience on parallel and distributed systems focusing on low level development. With my experience, I learned to tackle several tasks to improve problem-solving skills, and increase my knowledge about tools and technologies. In each of those years, I developed and increased my love for challenging tasks and the knowledge that comes with every task solved.

Work Experience

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC)

Florianópolis, SC

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Feb. 2015 - Aug. 2018

- Developed a parallel framework port that focus on CPU and GPU computation to a low-power processor in C++ and a proprietary processor library.
- The ported framework enabled a lower power consumption in comparison with general processors.

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC)

Florianópolis, SC

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Feb. 2019 - Nov. 2022

- Developed a methodology to mimic memory accesses from an application running on a host SO.
- Applied the methodology in a distributed OS running on a high performance and low power consumption processor.
- · The methodology was able to mimic the behavior of applications on the distributed OS even without the needed support.
- This project was developed in Python and C.

Université Grenoble Alpes (UGA)

Grenoble, France

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Sept. 2019 - Nov. 2019

Rolo Harizanta MG

• Improved the developed methodology in a rich environment with authorities in the High Performance Computing area.

Honors & Awards

| 2021 | Finalist, Total Marathon of Farattet Frogramming | beio nonzonie, mo |
|------|--|-------------------|
| 2018 | Bachelor Honors Degree, Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC) | Florianópolis, SC |
| 2017 | Best scientific initiation work in Departamento de Informática e Estátistica (INE), Seminário de | Florianópolis, SC |
| 2017 | Iniciação Científica e Tecnológica da UFSC (SIC-UFSC) | rionanopolis, sc |
| 2017 | Second Place, 12th Marathon of Parallel Programming | Campinas, SP |

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python Advanced Advanced

USED THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION AND SEVERAL PROJECTS.

Finalist 16th Marathon of Parallol Programming

C Advanced

USED THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION AND SEVERAL PROJECTS.

C++ Intermediate

USED THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION AND SEVERAL PROJECTS.

Java Intermediate

USED IN A COUPLE OF YEARS IN MY COMPUTER SCIENCE COURSE.

Javascript Beginner - Intermediate

USED IN PROJECTS AFTER MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION TO LEARN ABOUT NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES.

PHP Beginner - Intermediate

USED IN PROJECTS AFTER MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION TO LEARN ABOUT NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES.

CSS Beginner - Intermediate

USED IN PROJECTS AFTER MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION TO LEARN ABOUT NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES.

LANGUAGES

Brazilian Portuguese Native

English Advanced, Fluent

ALWAYS SEARCHING FOR NEW WAYS TO IMPROVE MY COMMUNICATION.

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

High Performance Computing Advanced

USING THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION.

Distributed Systems Advanced

USING THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION.

Parallel Computing Advanced

USING THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION.

Linux Advanced

USING THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION UNTIL TODAY.

Git Intermediate

USING THROUGHOUT MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION UNTIL TODAY.

Wordpress Beginner - Intermediate

USED IN PROJECTS AFTER MY ACADEMIC EDUCATION TO LEARN ABOUT NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES.

MySQL Beginner - Intermediate

USED IN A COUPLE OF YEARS IN MY COMPUTER SCIENCE COURSE.

Travis CI Beginner

USED IN A PART OF MY MASTER'S PROJECT.

Jenkins Beginner

USED IN A PART OF MY MASTER'S PROJECT.

Presentations

36th ACM/SIGAPP Symposium On Applied Computing (SAC)

Virtual Conference PRESENTER FOR A TRACE-DRIVEN METHODOLOGY FOR DISTRIBUTED OSES Mar. 2021

- Introduced core concepts about High Performance Computing and power consumption.
- Discussed distributed OSes and how they improve High Performance Computing environment.
- · Presented a methodology proposal to solve problems inside this context.

18th Simpósio de Sistemas Computacionais de Alto Desempenho (WSCAD)

PRESENTER FOR POWER EFFICIENT APPLICATIONS EXECUTION FOR A LIGHTWEIGHT MANYCORE

• Introduced core concepts about High Performance Computing and power consumption.

- Discussed about frameworks for application execution.
- Presented an improvement on a framework to achieve better power efficiency.

Campinas, SP Oct. 2017

17° Escola Regional de Alto Desempenho do Estado do Rio Grande do Sul (ERAD/RS)

ljuí, RS

PRESENTER FOR A FRAMEWORK PSKEL IMPLEMENTATION WITH SUPPORT FOR ITERATIVE STENCIL APPLICATIONS ON MPPA-256

PROCESSOR

Apr. 2017

- Introduced core concepts about High Performance Computing and power consumption.
- Discussed about frameworks for application execution.
- Presented an improvement on a framework to achieve better power efficiency.

16° Escola Regional de Alto Desempenho do Estado do Rio Grande do Sul (ERAD/RS)

São Leopoldo, RS

PRESENTER FOR PSKEL-MPPA: A PSKEL FRAMEWORK PORT TO MPPA-256 MANYCORE PROCESSOR

Apr. 2016

- Introduced core concepts about High Performance Computing and power consumption.
- Discussed about frameworks for application execution.
- Presented initial concepts to improve a framework to achieve better power efficiency.

Education

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC)

Florianópolis, SC

BACHELOR DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2013 - Aug. 2018

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC)

Florianópolis, SC

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Feb. 2019 - Nov. 2022

Extracurricular Activity

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC)

Florianópolis, SC

TEACHING ASSISTANT ON PARALLEL AND DISTRIBUTED PROGRAMMING CLASS

Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2019

- Helped the teacher with the creation and review of documents, and presentations for the class.
- Helped on the creation of several problems for the students.
- Answered conceptual questions from students, and helped them with bugs and questions.